Joshua Richards

Software Engineer

Email: jmrichards96@gmail.com Cell: (860) 951-6629

Cell: (860) 951-6629 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/j-richards

Digital Resume: www.jrichards.space
Address: 153 Grevstone Ln. Apt 12

153 Greystone Ln, Apt 12 Rochester, NY 14618

Summary

I am a full-stack (primarily front-end) developer with experience ranging from web APIs to embedded systems. I have a passion for learning new technologies to implement projects both effectively and efficiently.

Skills

Technologies: JavaScript/TypeScript, ES6, Node.js, CSS, HTML, C#, C++, Git **Other:**

- Ability to handle numerous responsibilities and desire to learn required skills
- Experience working in an agile development environment, implementing project features over a series of iterations within a release cycle

Experience

Carrier Global Corporation

Software Engineer

Pittsford, NY

Aug 27, 2018 - Present

- Responsible for the development of a web-based video streaming interface for security applications (with technologies including ES6, TypeScript, Node.is, RxJS, WebSockets).
 - Technical lead of the project from January, 2020 to August, 2020.
- Recently responsible for development work on one of the applications that uses the streaming interface mentioned above (with technologies including Node.js, React, Redux).
 - Team lead from May, 2021 to Present.
- Utilizing services such as Rally, GitHub, Jenkins (CI/CD), and Azure.

Gerber Technology

Tolland, CT

Software Engineering Intern

June 4, 2018 - Aug 10, 2018

• Responsible for the development of a variety of safety enhancements to a material spreading system (with C++).

EagleDream Technologies

Web Developer Co-op

Rochester, NY

Aug 28, 2017 - Dec 15, 2017

 Responsible for the development of various fit for purpose websites (with technologies including JavaScript, C#, SQL, CSS, Sass, WordPress, Shopify, PHP).

Gerber Technology

Tolland, CT

Software Engineering Intern

June 5, 2017 - Aug 11, 2017

 Responsible for the development of a material cutting system's label printing interface (with C#, XAML, SQL, WPF).

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY

Bachelor of Science in Game Design and Development

May 2019

Minor in Computer Science

GPA: 3.58

Projects/Labs

- Developed TaskApp, a project task organizer, with technologies including Express, React, MongoDB, Redis, Gulp, and Sass.
- Developed the game Serpentine as an individual project with Unity and C# and published it to the Google Play store.
- As part of a team of five developed HealthNet, a management system for a collection of hospitals, employees, and patients with Django, a Python Web framework.